A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
- LETTERS
  - Mary C. Day, Wellsville, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Sep 20; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
  - Carl Busch, Conductor, Kansas City Symphony Orchestra, Kansas City, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Sep 25; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    expressing his interest in having her poetry set to some `Ozark songs'
  - Harold Flammer, G. Schirmer, (Inc.), New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Sep 28; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to use her lyrics "A Benediction" in a musical setting by C. Whitney Coombs
  - Alice B. Long, West New Brighton, New York, to Charles Scribner & Sons, 1916 Oct 6; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 7)
    asking permission to use the second verse of Sara Teasdale's poem "Child, Child" on a card to be distributed among friends
  - James Bird, Marietta, Ohio, to Scribner's Magazine, 1916 Oct 7; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to set to music Sara Teasdale's poem "Child, Child"
  - H. L. Mencken, Editor, Smart Set, [Baltimore, Maryland], to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 7; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    expressing his pleasure at her new poems, and mentioning the protest against the Post Office banning of the works of Theodore Dreiser
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning letters requesting permission to use some of Sara's lyrics
  - Editors, Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 14; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    accepting her poem "Other Men" for publication
  - Girard Blair, The Sedalia National Bank, Sedalia, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 21; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to set to music her poems "Deep in the Night," "Come," and "The Flight"
  - Paul L. Benjamin, Anti-Tuberculosis Committee, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 23; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting an original verse to use as a guide for contestants in a health poetry contest in which Harriet Monroe, Henry Adams Bellows, and William Stanley Braithwaite will act as judges
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, to Elsa Barker, Duffield & Company, Publishers, Los Angeles, California, 1916 Oct 24; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to use one of her poems in an anthology she is editing entitled
    The Answering Voice--One Hundred Love-Lyrics by Women
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    accepting her poem "August Moonrise" for publication if conditions are agreeable
  - Rosalie Day, Catskill, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Oct 31; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    asking her consent on behalf of her singing master to have a song published using her verse "Jewels"
  - Harriet Monroe, Editor, Poetry: A Magazine of Verse, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1916 Oct 31; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 7)
    commenting on the poems she liked best including a group of "Songs Out of Stress"
  - Gertrude M. Richards, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 4; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    admitting that she has been enthusiastically reading from Sara's poems at her Poetry Readings and asks for furthur cooperation
  - A. S. Berghauser, Tusculum College, Greenville, Tennessee, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Nov 5; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    seeking biographical information for their club studying living English and American poets
  - Julia R. Tutwiler, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Nov 8; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    writing as her agent and enclosing a check for her poem "The Philosopher" which is to be published in
    Good Housekeeping
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Nov 11; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    accepting her poem "The Ballad of St. Kevin" for their Christmas issue
  - Zella Estelle Leighton, Delaware, Ohio, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Nov 17; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to publish her poem "The Cloud" set to music
  - Maude Haben Luck, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Nov 20; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to publish "The Look" set to music along with some others she is working on
  - Edward Joseph O'Brien, South Yarmouth, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 20; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning a project with
    The Bookman
    and Dodd, Mead, & Company in the form of an anthology of new poems by American poets
  - Rosalie L. Hausmann, San Francisco, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 21; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to use some of her poems in musical settings
  - Julius Kranz, Glendale, California, to The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 22; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to use "The Cloud" and "Night Song at Amalfi" by Sara Teasdale in musical settings
  - Cora E. Large, North Tonawanda, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 27; ALS, 5 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    admiring her work and wondering how to obtain her books other than
  - Harold Strong Latham, Editor, The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 29; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    referring to a letter, November 22, 1916, from Julius Kranz
  - William J. Matheson, New York, New York, to Editor, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, 1916 Nov 29; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    admiring Sara Teasdale's "November Night" and commenting on its "wonderful imagery, its sympathetic feeling..."
  - Oscar Leonard, St. Louis, Missouri, to Ernst B. Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    translating a reference to
    from Yiddish to English
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 4; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    referring to a note in praise of her "November Night"
  - Julia R. Tutwiler, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 5; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    writing as her agent and sending a check for "Spring Rain" which is to be published in
    Century Magazine
  - Edward C. Murch, The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 11; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    offering an agreement for her proposal of a book of `Love Lyrics'
  - Rudolph Altrocchi, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 12; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    writing of entertaining friends with a reading of her
    and their enjoyment
  - Edward C. Murch, The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 14; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    sending the agreement for the proposed book of love lyrics
  - Henry Gray Glover, Jackson, Michigan, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 21; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
  - Harold Vincent Milligan, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Dec 28; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning the publication of several of his songs made from her lyrics
  - Robert Gilbert Welsh, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, [1916]; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    acknowledging her letter and volume of verse
  - Lee Shippey, President, Missouri Writers Guild, Higginsville, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Jan 3; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    inviting her to talk intimately about her work at the Writers Guild Day at the University of Missouri
  - Dorothy Furman, Glen Ridge, New Jersey, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Jan 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting one of her bookplates in exchange for the enclosed one of her own
  - Walter de la Mare, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Jan 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    expressing his enjoyment in reading her poems, particularly "I Shall Not Care," "Off Algiers," and "Capri"
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Jan 5; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    revealing that he would be pleased to have her work appear more often in the magazine
  - Embers McG[ ], Jackson, Michigan, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Jan 8; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    praising her poems in the form of a poem entitled "Why Not"
  - Carrie Bullard Lewis, Tufts College, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Jan 16; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use her poem "Grandfather's Love" in a musical setting for a colleciton of childrens' songs
  - Charles Hanson Towne, Editor, McClure's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Feb 14; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 8)
    accepting her poem "Tonight" for publication but declining "Defeated" due to spacing problems
  - Edith Lobdell, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Feb 16; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use her poem "Swans" in a musical setting
  - Virginia Roderick, Associate Editor, Everybody's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Feb 21; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    accepting her poem "Schooners" for publication
  - Alice Reber Fish, Brooklyn, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Feb 24; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to set to music her two poems "Joy" and "The Look"
  - Henry Adams Bellows, Associate Editor, The Bellman, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Mar 2; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    accepting her poem "The Strawberry Man" for publication, and expressing sympathy for her sickness
  - Burton E. Stevenson, Chillicothe, Ohio, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1917 Mar 27; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use a few of her lyrics in a revision of his "The Home Book of Verse"
  - William Withenow, Jr., Fremont, Michigan, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Apr 10; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    praising her poem "Dreams" and requesting permission to publish it in a musical setting
  - Gustav Davidson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Apr 20; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    concerning a magazine,
    The Madrigal
    , devoted to the publication of love lyrics and requesting a contribution
  - Edward J. O'Brien, Magdalen Islands, Canada, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Apr 23; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    expressing gratitude for her sending "At Midnight" which he will include in
    The Masque of Poets
    and send to
  - A. Walter Kramer, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Apr 30; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    revealing that he has set her poem "Swans" as a song after receiving a copy of her
  - Jane Leland Clarke, Coolidge Corner, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 May 4; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use her poem "Deep in the Night" for a musical setting
  - William Frederick Bigelow, Editor, Good Housekeeping Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 May 10; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    concerning the changed version of "The Prayer of the Gardener"
  - Hamilton Fish Armstrong, The New Republic, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 May 11; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    concerning a volume he is editing entitled
    The Book of New York Verse
    and wishing to include some of Sara's poems
  - Frances Evans Crawford, Irvington-on Hudson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 May 13; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    concerning a musical setting of her poem "Pierrot"
  - August L. Baug, Kenmare, North Dakota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 June 7; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    wishing to have published the enclosed Danish translation of her poem "Rain"
  - Amy M. Beach, Hillsboro, New Hampshire, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 June 22; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to publish a musical setting for women's chorus of her poem "Dusk in June"
  - Joseph Jackson, Worcester, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1917 June 25; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use her poem "Helen of Troy" in a collection of poems about ancient Troy
  - Sadie A. Frank, Nashville, Tennessee, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 July 7; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use her poem "Sea Longing" in a "book on modern tendencies of poetry as exhibited in the sonnet"
  - Edward J. Wheeler, Editor, Current Opinion, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 July 10; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    informing her that her poem-sequence "Songs Out of Sorrow" has received the highest vote in balloting of the Poetry Society of America
  - Blanche S. Wagstaff, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 July 26; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the letter and poem, and mentioning activities in the National League
  - Frank M. Beverly, Freeling, West Virginia, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 July 31; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    praising her poem "Tonight" and wishing to tell her about his own brand of poetry-making
  - Margaret W. Stevens, China, Maine, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Aug 2; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    expressing her feelings for the poems in
    , and commenting on their being "so simple and natural and real"
  - Winifred Russell, Gordonsville, Virginia, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Aug 8; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    seeking help in the way of reviewing with her own verses and asking where to obtain "Songs Out of Sorrow"
  - C. Wharton Stork, Contemporary Verse, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Aug 10; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    accepting her poem "Embers" and requesting material for a free ad
  - Jean Stansbury Holden, Tryon, North Carolina, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1917 Aug 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 8)
    praising her poem "Schooners" and inquiring about the names of the vessels
  - Aileen Cleveland Higgins, Duluth, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Aug 17; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting autographed volumes of
    to be auctioned for the American Ambulance Fund
  - Ralph T. Whitney, 29th Infantry Band, Camp Gaillaid, Culebra, Panama, to Editor, McClure's Magazine, New York, New York, 1917 Sep 5; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to publish Sara Teasdale's poem "Tonight" set to music
  - Harper & Brothers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Sep 7; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    concerning a request for permission to publish her poem "Buried Love" with a musical setting from Miss Mima A. Taylor of Kilmarnock, Scotland
  - Mrs. A. R. Wilson, Christiansburg, Virginia, to The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, 1917 Sep 11; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use Sara Teasdale's poem "The Look" in a musical setting to be published by Harold Flammer
  - Harold Strong Latham, The MacMillan Company, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1917 Sep 19; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 8)
    concerning the September 11 letter from Mrs. A. R. Wilson
  - Charles Hanson Towne, McClure's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Sep 20; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    [concerning Ralph T. Whitney]
  - Charles Hanson Towne, McClure's Magazine, New York, New York, to Ralph T. Whitney, Camp Gaillaid, Culebra, Panama, 1917 Sep 20; TL (carbon), 1 p. (Box Box 8)
    concerning his request of September 5
  - John Warren Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Ernst B. Filsinger and Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 3; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    praising Sara's love songs and commenting that the two books [
    Love Songs
    The Answering Voice: One Hundred Love Lyrics by Women
    ] are pretty, and writing family news
  - Henry J. Filsinger and Katherine Ernst Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the two books, one of love songs, the other a collection of poems by women
  - Theodore Roosevelt, Metropolitan, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 4; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the forthcoming volume and promising to read it with pleasure
  - Miles M. Dawson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 5; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the two volumes [
    ] and praising her own love songs as being of a higher level than the other women's verses
  - Joseph Kershaw, Plymouth, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 5; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    requesting permission to use her verse "Tonight" in a musical setting
  - H. L. Mencken, Editor, The Smart Set, Baltimore, Maryland, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 6; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the book of lyrics,
  - John Erskine, Columbia University, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 10; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    , and commenting on her "gift for pure lyric"
  - Fay Foster, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 11; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    , and finding in it verses for songs
  - Terry [ ], Housatonic, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Oct 11; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the book of her poems,
    , and commenting on its "lyric loveliness"
  - Padraic Colum, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Nov 4; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the inscribed
  - Amy Lowell, Brookline, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Nov 7; TLS, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    discussing Sara's
    and her own
    Cornucopia of Red and Green Comfits
    and Vachel Lindsay and his work
  - John Masefield, Boar's Hill, Oxford, England, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Nov 11; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the charming little book, [
  - Virginia Roderick, Associate Editor, Everybody's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Nov 22; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    accepting her poems "Sons" for the January issue and "When we are Happiest" for a later one
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Nov 30; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    accepting a poem for their Christmas issue
  - Editor, Harper's Magazine, Harper & Brothers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    accepting her poem "The Cup" for publication
  - John Masefield, Boar's Hill, Oxford, England, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Dec 7; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for the charming letter and gift of poems
  - Witter Bynner, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1917 Dec 14; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    praising her volume of poems,
    , and asking if she has any war poems to possibly read at the MacDowell Center
  - Edward J. Wheeler, Editor, Current Opinion, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1918 Jan 5; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    sending her a poem by himself entitled "Sara--An Acrostic"
  - Frank D. Fackenthal, Columbia University, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1918 June 7; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    informing her of the Poetry Society of America award for her volume
  - Edward C. Murch, The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1918 June 8; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    inquiring about the possibilities of further work
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Helen Truesdell Koch, Cleveland, Ohio, 1919 Mar 31; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    expressing gratitude for her letter and mentioning her own physical weakness
  - Williamina Parrish, Venezia, Italy, to Vine Colby McCasland, St. Louis, Missouri, 1919 May 13; APCS (Box Box 8)
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Vine Colby McCasland, St. Louis, Missouri, 1922 Dec 21; APCS (Box Box 8)
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger to Vine Colby McCasland, [1922 Dec]; APCS (Box Box 8)
    mentioning
    , and asking after her family
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Barbara Crary George, Kansas City, Missouri, 1926 May 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    commenting on the latter's verses and encouraging her
  - Edwin Arlington Robinson, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1926 Oct 27; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    thanking her for her book and telling of his enjoyment in reading it
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Brook Bend Tavern, Monterey, Massachusetts, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1930 Aug 10; ALS, 10 p. on 3 l. (Box Box 9)
    writing to her friend after a long interval, telling of her separation from Ernst B. Filsinger, a visit in May to France with Margaret Conklin, her problems since being seriously injured in a taxi-cab in March 1928, and plans for a visit to California
  - Susan Meriwether Boogher Bryan, Havre De Grace, Maryland, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1930 Dec 20; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
    reviving ties with her old friend
  - Susan Meriwether Boogher Bryan, Havre De Grace, Maryland, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1931 Dec 21; ALS, 6 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 8)
    exchanging family news, and mentioning Joseph Hergesheimer
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1932 Mar 4; ALS, 10 p. on 10 l. (Box Box 9)